tastebuds.fm 2019-03-09

# Privacy Policy - Tastebuds

This privacy policy explains how we (Tastebuds Media Ltd.) collect, use, share and transfer your personal data on Tastebuds.fm (the "Site") and our related mobile applications ("our apps"). 

Personal data is any information about you by which you are identified or could be identified. This can include information such as: 

  * your name,
  * date of birth,
  * email address,
  * gender
  * favourite artists
  * location
  * information about your device (such as the IP address, which is a numerical code to identify your device that can provide information about the country, region or city where you are based); and
  * information relating to your personal circumstances and how you use our site and our apps.

Sometimes our site or apps may contain links to third party websites and services. These websites and services have their own privacy policies. If you follow a link to a third party, you should read the privacy policy shown on their site. 

The Privacy Policy is intended to describe for you, as an individual who is a user of the Site or of the services offered on the Site (collectively with the Site, the "Services"), the information we collect, how that information may be used, with whom it may be shared, and your choices about such uses and disclosures. 

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using the Services. By accessing the Services, you acknowledge and agree that you have read, fully accept, and will abide by this Privacy Policy. 

* ### 1\. Who we are and Contact

The data controller for our site and our apps is Tastebuds Media Limited, 33 Inkerman Road, NW5 3BT, London. This means that we are responsible for deciding how and why we hold and use your personal data. 

Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy, the way in which we use information we hold about you, if you would like to obtain a copy of the personal data we hold on you, or if you wish to make a complaint or comment: write to us at: [hello@tastebuds.fm](mailto:%68%65%6c%6c%6f@%74%61%73%74%65%62%75%64%73.%66%6d) .

Complaints will be dealt with by the Data Protection Manager, and will be responded to within 30 days. 

* ### 2\. Your Data

**Collecting and using your personal data**

We collect personal data about you when you sign up for our Tastebuds services and when you browse our site or when you use our apps. This information is used to provide the Tastebuds services and analyse how visitors use our site or apps. 

We collect personal data when you: 

  * register for a Tastebuds account;
  * provide information about yourself in your Tastebuds profile;
  * access our site and apps, through cookies and other similar technology; and
  * contact our customer service team.

The personal data we collect from you when you register as a member and why we use this information When you register to become a Tastebuds member we collect: 

  * your email address;
  * your username;
  * your password;
  * your location;
  * your date of birth; and
  * your profile picture if you choose to provide a picture.

You can also add pictures to your gallery. You can add any pictures from your Facebook account, you will be redirected to your Facebook account for this. We only receive these pictures and no other information about your Facebook profile. 

**Special categories of data**

When you complete your Tastebuds profile we ask you about your gender and whether you are looking to meet women or men. We only collect this information in order to provide you with the appropriate matches. We will not collect any other special categories of data - such as information about your race, political opinions, religion, or health - unless you have chosen to provide that information to us. 

**Using our apps**

The Tastebuds apps use information on the content you have viewed and the actions you have taken. The pictures that you have viewed are temporarily cached in the local storage on your mobile device. 

Information on what you have viewed in the apps, actions you have taken and information on bugs and crashes is also sent to us. You can choose to receive notifications on your mobile device via the apps. You can manage these notification in the settings of the apps. 

**Who can see your Tastebuds profile pictures**

If you choose to add a profile picture, this will be displayed to anyone who views your profile page or sees you on a search results page. Your profile picture may be included in email communications to Tastebuds members if we consider you to be a good match. 

**Who can see your Tastebuds profile information**

Your Tastebuds username will be made public on the Tastebuds services and this will be the identity by which you are known on the Tastebuds services. Visitors to Tastebuds who have not logged in will be able to see limited information about you (your username, picture, description of yourself, favourite musical artists, and what you are looking for, basic information about your age, approximate location, height, and so on). 

Tastebuds members who are logged in can see all of the information you have put in your profile. Always think carefully about the information you put on your profile. As we have said in our terms of use, it is your responsibility to decide what information you want to make available to other Tastebuds members or other internet users. 

**Updating your personal data and your Tastebuds profile page**

You may access and update your personal data by logging into your account and going to the "Your account" and "Edit profile" sections. You must make sure that you update your information as soon as possible with all relevant changes. In the "Your account" section you may also update your marketing and communications preferences. 

**Additional information we collect when you use our site or our apps**

We collect additional information about you when you use our site or our apps. This includes the following: 

  * messages sent between Tastebuds members. Your safety is important to us, so we check some messages sent between Tastebuds members for inappropriate content. As shown in our terms of use, we can delete inappropriate content; and
  * your customer service history, including your correspondence with us.

When you use our site or apps we may also use cookies or similar technology to collect additional information, including: 

  * your IP address - a numerical code to identify your device and which can provide information about the country, region or city where you are based;
  * your browsing history of the content you have visited on our site, including information on how you were referred to our site via another website; and
  * details of your devices, for example, the unique device ID, unique advertising ID and browsers used to access our content.

**Why we use your personal data**

We use the personal data collected through our sites and apps for a number of purposes, including the following: 

  * To provide the Tastebuds services you sign up for, for example, sending service emails, informing the algorithm used to find you the best matches with regard to your location and other preferences, and related internal administrative purposes (such as those we need for our accounting and records) and to make you aware of any changes to our services;
  * Sending you marketing communications when we have your permission, or when permitted by law;
  * To improve our marketing, we use a similar technology to cookies to confirm whether you have opened a marketing email or clicked on a link in the email;
  * Personalising our services for you (for example, so you can log in), remembering your settings, recognising you when you log into your account on different devices and tailoring your emails based on the information provided on your Tastebuds profile;
  * For statistical purposes, such as analysing the performance of our site and apps and to understand how visitors use them;
  * To respond to your queries and resolve complaints;
  * For security and fraud prevention and to ensure that our site and apps are safe, secure and used in line with our terms of use. For example, we collect our members’ date of birth to ensure they are at least 18 years; and
  * To comply with applicable laws and regulations.

**Access permissions that we ask from users of the Tastebuds apps**

When you use the Tastebuds apps, we will also ask for the following permissions to access particular functions of your mobile device: 

  * We ask for permission to use your location, so that we can show you matches nearby;
  * We ask for permission to access your camera and photo library, so that you can add your own pictures for your profiles gallery; and
  * We ask for permission to send you notifications, for example if someone has sent you a message to your Tastebuds inbox.

* ### 3\. Your data rights

If you would like to have a copy of the personal data we hold on you or if you think that we hold incorrect personal data about you, please email [hello@tastebuds.fm](mailto:%68%65%6c%6c%6f@%74%61%73%74%65%62%75%64%73.%66%6d) . We will deal with requests for copies of your personal data or for correction of your personal data within one month. If your request is complicated or if you have made a large number of requests, it may take us longer. We will let you know if we need longer than one month to respond. 

You will not have to pay a fee to obtain a copy of your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Where you have provided us with consent to use your personal data, you can withdraw this at any time. 

* ### 4\. Legal grounds for using your personal data

We will only use your personal data where we have a legal ground to do so. We determine the legal grounds based on the purposes for which we have collected and used your personal data. In every case, the legal ground will be one of the following: 

**Performance of a contract with you (or in order to take steps prior to entering into a contract with you):**

For example, where you have purchased a subscription from us and we need to use your contact details in order to process your order and deliver your subscription.

**Consent:**

For example, where you have provided your consent to receive marketing emails from us. You can withdraw your marketing consent at any time, including by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the email or through your email preferences on your profile tab, when you are logged into your account. We also rely on your consent for using your profile picture and profile for promotional purposes. You can withdraw your consent at any time in "Your account" preferences.

**Our legitimate interests:**

Where it is necessary for us to understand our customers, promote our services and operate our site efficiently for the provision of our services. For example, we will rely on our legitimate interest when we carry out marketing analysis to understand our customers to determine what marketing communications may be relevant to them. It is also in our legitimate interest to analyse what content has been viewed on our site and apps, so that we can understand how they are used.

**Compliance with law:**

In some cases, we may have a legal obligation to use or keep your personal data.

* ### 5\. Your password

You can only access your account information and our service through the use of your username and password. To protect the confidentiality of your personal data, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. As it is not stored in plaintext, your password is hashed using a one-way hashing algorithm which means it cannot be recovered (or disclosed) by anyone, including ourselves, it can only be reset. Please notify us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. Please note, we will never ask you to disclose your password.

* ### 6\. Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on your hard drive that allows us to recognise your computer from one page access to the next. We use persistent cookies in order to keep you logged in to the site after you close your browser. We therefore recommended logging out of the site on shared computers after use.

If for any reason you decide that you do not want all of your Tastebuds activities to be stored you may set your browser and mobile settings to block cookies and local storage devices, but please remember that if you do so, you may not be able to access all of the features Tastebuds offers. For example, the login process and all member functionality requires that your browser accept cookies.

You can also visit the trade body representing the advertising companies for more information on how to opt out of all such cookies: www.youronlinechoices.com

The cookies we collect enable us to learn how people interact with Tastebuds, which in turn helps us make a better product for you. Cookies store information about your website visits and can recognise you and your preferences each time you visit Tastebuds. They help us to provide a better service to you. We use the following types of cookies: 

**Analytics and research** We use Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use the App. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the App. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the App, where visitors have come from and the pages they visited. For more information about Google's Privacy Policy, please visit <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/>

**Authentication** These cookies help us identify our Users so that when you're logged in you can enjoy our offerings, experiences and various features, such as uploading photographs and chatting. You can even localise your experience, such as when you've requested to view the App in your local language or when you ask Tastebuds to 'remember me'. These cookies also help us to remember who invited you to join Tastebuds. We also use cookies and other web technologies, such as CAPTCHAs, to help keep Tastebuds and our members safe and secure. 

**Security and site integrity** We may use persistent cookies, which will help us to ensure we have identified the same device is logging into the correct account. These cookies help us combat the bad guys - they help with our anti-spam measures and may help us to prevent phishers, scammers, unauthorised log-in attempts to your Account and accessing any hacked accounts. 

**Site features and services** These cookies and local storage devices provide functionality such as uploading photographs, chat, instant messaging, and using your Account settings. They also help provide experiences, such as links to other social media sites, social plugins and video content, including making it easier for you to share content between Tastebuds and your other favorite social networks. In some cases, we may allow a third party to place cookies or save data to your local storage devices on your mobile device – this is where Tastebuds's Privacy Policy ends and theirs begin. The third party who places cookies on your device is responsible for how they process their data so you should read their privacy policies and make sure you're okay with them before you start sharing. Examples of such policies are available at the following links: Twitter: https://twitter.com/privacy Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/policy.php YouTube: http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/ 

We may also track IP addresses. An IP Address is a number that can identify an Internet Service Provider, country location etc. It cannot provide personal information. We will not use the IP Address to build a profile on users, we only use the information for demographic, statistical and security purposes.

* ### 7\. How do we use personal and other data?

By providing us with your personal data and agreeing to the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy you are giving your consent: for us to process your personal data (including any sensitive personal data such as your sexual orientation) for the purposes of providing the Services and for any other purposes which you have given your express consent to; and to the transfer and processing of your information in countries outside the European Economic Area which may not provide the same level of data protection as the UK. If we do make such a transfer or if your personal information will be processed outside the European Economic Area, we will put a contract in place to ensure your information is protected or where applicable covered by the US 'Privacy Shield Program'. We may also use your information to help us to analyse use of the service and the Services and to improve the Services and their content or to troubleshoot problems and implement the Terms. Your personal data will only be processed by authorised staff members (or by such third parties as we may use from time to time to store and process data for us). 

* ### 8\. Deleting your information

You have the option to deactivate your profile at any time which will remove it from public view on our system.

We recommend you deactivate your profile if you are not using Tastebuds any more. If you change your mind in the future, you can return to your profile any time within two years and 'reactivate' your profile without losing any of your information.

If you would like to permanently delete your account please visit the Settings page of the site. Follow the links to Deactivate and then Permanently Delete your account under the 'Account' tab. Deletion will permanently remove your photos and profile information from our database. Support enquiries sent to us may be stored on file.

If your profile has been deleted because you have contravened our Terms of Use, we reserve the right to keep some or all of your personal data for up to 10 years from the date of deletion, in order to help protect other members, prevent fraud and to enable us to assist the Police or other law enforcement authorities if legally required to do so.

We keep your data for only as long as we need to. How long we need your personal data depends on what we are using it for. For example, we may need it to use it to answer your queries about our services or where required by law. If you decide to take a break from Tastebuds and deactivate your profile, we will not show your profile on the Tastebuds services and you will not appear in anyone's search results or emails of suggested matches.

If you do not return to your Tastebuds profile within two years or if there is a lack of activity on your profile within those two years, we may decide to delete your personal data or make it anonymous by removing all your details.

If we have asked for your permission to process your personal data and we have no other lawful grounds to continue with that processing, and you withdraw your permission, we will delete your personal data. However, when you unsubscribe from marketing communications, we will keep your email address to ensure that we do not send you any marketing communications in future.

* ### 9\. Internal use of information

We may internally use your information to improve our services, analyse site usage, optimise content, etc. This will only be conducted by authorised staff members of Tastebuds.fm. We may use personally identifiable information to troubleshoot problems and implement our terms and conditions.

* ### 10\. Disclosure of your information

Our general disclosure policy is as follows:

  * We will not disclose any of your information without your permission.
  * We will not supply any Member's details to any other Member - please don't even ask us.
  * We will not sell or rent or give your information to any third party unless you give us permission to do so.
  * We will only disclose your information if legally obligated to do so by a statutory authority with the appropriate jurisdiction.

* ### 11\. Personal correspondence

Correspondence sent to us including emails and letters will be stored on file with access limited to our authorised staff members.

* ### 12\. How we may contact you

You will receive essential service emails, for example, telling you that your subscription is coming to an end or sending you a payment confirmation. The Tastebuds service includes update emails, including information on your new matches, new likes and new messages.

You can choose not to receive these update emails in the 'Notifications' section of the Settings page when signed in to your account or using the link at the bottom of the email. 

* ### 13\. Security

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational controls to protect your personal data against unauthorised processing and against accidental loss, damage or destruction. You are responsible for choosing a secure password when we ask you to set up a password to access parts of our site or apps. You should keep this password confidential and you should choose a password that you do not use on any other site. You should not share your password with anyone else, including anyone who works for us.

Unfortunately, sending information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data once with us, we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data sent to our site while still in transit and so you provide it at your own risk.

WE EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM ANY REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO ANY BREACHES OF SECURITY, DAMAGE TO YOUR DEVICE, OR ANY LOSS OR UNAUTHORIZED USE OF YOUR REGISTRATION INFORMATION OR OTHER DATA.

* ### 14\. Changes to this policy

If we make material changes to our privacy policy, these changes will be posted to our privacy policy page. You should review this page regularly for updates.
